A Guide to the Near East Foundation records Accessions 2009.104, 2010.002, 2010.020 FA406
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Near East Foundation films, 42 film reels 42 Film Reels, NEF Foundation film collection encompasses approximately 18,000 feet of film on 42 reels. The collection includes 1 negative and 41 prints in 16mm and 35mm formats.
  - Here They Are in Their True Colors, 1955; Silent, Tinting/Toning. Due to high shrinkage, do not project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, Kodacolor. (Reel AV 995)
  - W2C, 1953; Sound, Black & White, 1 minutes. Condition is good. Safe to project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, 42 feet. (Reel AV 996)
    Footage from a conference showcasing the table for "The American Friends of the Middle East"
  - Athens - Iran, 1968; Silent, Color, 10 minutes. Condition is good. Safe to project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, 369 feet, Kodachrome. (Reel AV 997)
    Footage of ancient architecture in Athens including the Acropolis and ampitheaters. Some trades are demonstrated such as iron refurbishing, manikin making, and broom making. Children wave to camer then show some athletic activities.
  - The Story of Merj, 1951-1971; Sound, Black & White, 14 minutes. Condition is good. Safe to project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, 509 feet. (Reel AV 998)
    Footage of current agricultural technologies and tasks such as water collecting and tending the livestock. Men can be seen having discussions at a meeting while women and children visit the doctor. Same as AV 998. Same as AV 970.
  - Israel, 1958; Silent, Color, 10 minutes. Condition is good. Safe to project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, 352 feet, Kodachrome. (Reel AV 999)
    Amateur film of the city and the surrounding rural areas. A look at the life of a local village.
  - Egypt 1959, 1964; Silent, Color, 19 minutes. Condition is good. Safe to project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, 675 feet, Kodachrome. (Reel AV1000)
    Footage of sights one can see in Egypt. Architectural buildings such as temples are admired. Sailboats can be seen on the river. Even some views of the streets are present.
  - Holy Land - Jerusalem - Emmans, 1958; Silent, Color, 5 minutes. Condition is good. Safe to project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, 186 feet, Kodachrome, Awind. (Reel AV 1001)
    Footage of city. Some rocky hills on the outskirts are explored and and a stone table is a point of interest.
  - Athens, 1968; Silent, Color, 7 minutes. Condition is good. Safe to project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, 237 feet, Kodachrome, Awind. (Reel AV 1002)
    Film sppears to be a video following patients in a Grecian hospital/ clinic. A nurse and some patients are introduced. A handicapped man demonstrates how to exercise and a boy is taought how to lace a boot. School children demostrate exercise regimen. Same as 1003
  - Athens #2, 1969; Silent, Color, 10 minutes. Condition is good. Safe to project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, 369 feet, Kodachrome, Awind. (Reel AV 1003)
    Film sppears to be a video following patients in a Grecian hospital/ clinic. A nurse and some patients are introduced. A handicapped man demonstrates how to exercise and a boy is taought how to lace a boot. School children demostrate exercise regimen. Same as 1002
  - Athens - City, Acropolis, etc., 1969; Silent, Color, 11 minutes. Condition is good. Safe to project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, 382 feet, Kodachrome, Awind. (Reel AV 1004)
    Footage of ancient architecture in Athens including the Acropolis and ampitheaters. Some natural sites are visited such as some rocky hills and floral gardens.
  - Tour the Holy Land, 1961; Silent, Color, 31 minutes. Condition is good. Safe to project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, 1142 feet, Eastman Color. (Reel AV 1673)
    A Summary of the trip taken to the Middle East. Footage incorporates tourist attractions such as the Egyptian Pyramids and religious sites while also including rural landscapes and the locals who inhabit the area. Lastly, visitors also enjoyed the nearby sea/river.
  - #1-#5, 1956; Silent, Black & White/ Color. Due to high shrinkage, do not project.; 16mm, Acetate, print, Kodachrome. (Reel AV 1742)
- Near East Foundation audio
  - Sadik Al-Assad, Nuhad J. Daghir -I / Nuhad J. Daghir -2, Rajah Tannous (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6896)
  - Dr. Winnie Huoho - 2, Blind woman, anatomy class, Wayne Jones (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6897)
  - [Untitled] (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6898)
  - HAMLIN HOSPITAL: Linda Londers (tours), children's song - Nasla Vuch / Dr. Charles K. Nucho -I (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6899)
  - Abdul Latif El-Zerin - 2, Nasri S. Kawar - I / Paris Andreou XI, Abdul Latif El-Zein - I (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6900)
  - [Untitled] (1/4 inch audio cassette AV 6901)